Whether for internal customers or external
customers, etiquette and professional conduct
are very important when troubleshooting a
network situation.
Think about it: Having any part of a network
down is a high-stress situation.
We, as network administrators, want to calm
the situation down, not make it worse.
Thus, here are some key factors to follow
as they relate to etiquette and professional
conduct.
First, avoid jargon.
Explanations to customers should be clear
and concise.
Secondly, maintain a positive attitude and
project confidence.
Assure customers the problem will be solved
but be honest about the time it may take;
this includes situations in which you are
dealing with difficult customers.
Thirdly, listen actively.
Avoid interrupting a customer.
Fourth, be culturally sensitive.
Use titles when possible.
Fifth, be on time.
Sixth, avoid distractions such as personal
calls and social media messages while troubleshooting
a problem.
Finally, keep confidential data confidential.
Avoid the temptation to look at data that
is left out but should not be left out.